Hi dear students, welcome back to our class.
Now in this second part of our lecture let's move to the theoretical lecture itself which
I have been talking about you and
our lecture will be from this book
which is by
Judith Boss and I put the details in the syllabus and the book name is Think Critical Thinking
and Logical Skills for
for everyday life. Okay.
And there are
newer versions of this book, which you can find from internet, but the version that doesn't
matter. Okay. But myself, I couldn't find the PDF version.
Probably you guys may
think this
can do this. Okay. And let me share the PPT file with you guys.
And okay, just a minute.
Okay, so let's start from chapter one, which is about
thinking critically, okay?
Critical thinking, why it's important, okay?
And let's start with some cases.
Okay, I hope my screen is okay and it's visible to you guys.
And
in 1960, as you guys can see in your screen, The Nazi war criminal
called
Adolf
Eichmann
was brought to court for the
crimes against humanity, okay?
And despite his claim
that he was just following the orders of his superiors when he ordered the deaths
of millions of Jews, the court still found him guilty, okay?
And sentenced him to death, okay?
So the question is,
was this guy an inhumane monster or he was just following the orders of his superiors?
In order to find more clear answers to these questions,
in the following decades, some professors of well-known universities
conducted certain
experiments. One of them was conducted by
Professor Social Psychologist Stanley Milgram of Yale
University. Let's watch a short video about this experiment.
Because I believe that the video can explain much better than me.
So let's watch this together.
Are ordinary people able to do terrible things?
Okay,
let me share that screen with you guys.
And sound is on. I hope this is visible to you guys.
Okay, let's start.
And if so, how many would give a strong electric shock to an innocent other just because they
are following an order? To answer these questions, we can look at the controversial work of
a man who just wanted to find answers to his family's horrific past.
In 1961, Stanley Milgram, a young psychologist, wanted to find out how ordinary citizens
were able to commit acts of unspeakable evil in Nazi Germany.
His theory? Some people do horrific things because they obey even the most wicked leaders.
To test his theory, Milgram designed a clever experiment that changed our understanding of
human behavior forever.
The Milgram experiment involved three people, an authority, called the Experimenter, who was
dressed in a lab coat to appear powerful, a volunteer, who was assigned to be the teacher,
and a victim, the so-called student.
The teacher was the test subject, whereas the Experimenter and student were both actors.
Following orders, the teacher would test a student who was sitting in another room by asking
them questions. For every wrong answer, the experimenter would ask the teacher to inflict an
electric shock up to a life-threatening 450 volts.
Before he began, Milgram asked his colleagues what they expected the outcome to be.
Almost all of them agreed that only a few of the volunteers would obey and inflict electric
shocks on innocent others.
What do you think? Would anyone administer shocks higher than 300 volts?
Milgram then advertised his experiment as a study on memory and learning at the campus of Yale
University. People signed up without any idea of what they were really getting themselves into.
The experiment began with the volunteers meeting the other participants.
The volunteers then pulled a card to draw their role.
Little did they know that they could only draw the teacher.
Next, they would be given a sample of a light electric shock in order to experience firsthand
what the others would have to go through.
To start, the experimenter and the teacher were seated in one room, and the student was strapped
to a chair in an adjacent room.
The teacher and student were able to communicate, but not see each other.
The experimenter then gave the teacher a list of questions.
The teacher would then read out the questions and the student would press a button to indicate
a response. For every false answer, the teacher would administer a shock starting at 15 volts
and increasing in 15 volt increments up to 450.
What the teacher didn't know was that the student didn't actually receive any shocks.
Instead, a tape recorder was used to play various responses.
In the beginning, the teacher would hear a protest or bangs against the wall.
If shocks would increase, the reactions would become louder.
And in case someone would go all the way, the learner would fall silent.
In case the teacher became hesitant and asked to stop, the experimenter would resort to the
following four prompts.
First, he would say, please continue.
If that was unsuccessful, he would go on with, the experiment requires that you continue.
Then, it is absolutely essential that you continue.
And lastly, you have no other choice.
You must go on.
Along the way, the volunteers displayed signs of extreme tension such as sweating, trembling,
and even uncontrollable laughing fits.
The experiment would be stopped only after all four prompts had been used or the maximum voltage
of 450 volts had been given three times.
Milgram found that, of all participants, 100% gave at least 300 volts and
65% went all the way to 450 volts.
The experiment was later criticized for being unethical because it deceived innocent people
into performing what seemed to be terrible acts of violence.
However, his experiment was successfully replicated many times, involving different populations
and leading to similar findings.
Milgram himself left us with this to think about.
It may be that we are puppets, puppets controlled by the strings of society.
But at least we are puppets with perception, with awareness, and perhaps, our awareness is
the first step to our liberation.
What do you think? Would you follow or question the orders if you were one of Milgram's participants?
And what can we as a society teach future generations to help prevent horrific acts that can
happen when ordinary people blindly follow an authority?
Let us know your thoughts in the comments below.
Okay guys,
let me go back to the
screen to my screen one second
okay guys I hope you understood the case right
it's a very interesting
experiment
and in case if you want to explore more on this experiment there are much longer videos in
YouTube you can search with this kind of terms and Milgram
experiment and there are
actually videos of that science, okay, from that time, okay?
And the questions here, I mean, which we can ask ourselves is that how could this happen, right?
And were the results some sort of deviation from normality, right?
And
while you guys are thinking
about these questions, let's watch
some more similar case, similar
experiment, which was conducted at Stanford University.
OK,
let me share this.
One second.
Oops, what happened?
Okay. One second. Uh,
something happened.
Okay. Let me type this.
In 2015, the Stanford Prison Experiment was released in theaters.
The movie detailed the infamous 1971 experiment in which 24 college students were put in prison.
Now, while the experiment was supposed to last for two weeks, it was terminated after six days
due to psychological effects that it was having on both the guards and the prisoners.
so what actually happened during the stanford prison experiment why is it so infamous and does
the movie get everything right or is it just a dramatization this video will briefly explain
the experiment its impact on the world of psychology and the controversy that it's facing 45
years in the future So, first off, what is the Stanford Prison Experiment?
After Milgram's experiment rocked the world of psychology, many people were left with questions
about obedience, power dynamics, and the abuse of power.
Philip Zimbardo, a professor at Stanford, wanted to then explore these questions further.
And with a grant from the Navy, Zimbardo set up something called the Stanford Prison Experiment.
He wanted to see, could a person's role influence their behavior?
Zimbardo and his team interviewed 70 applicants at Stanford who were willing to participate
in the study for 14 days and receive $15 a day.
They wanted to make sure that they chose the brightest and the most mentally sound participants.
And after narrowing down their applicants to 24, the researchers flipped the coin and assigned
the roles. Half of the participants would be prisoners and the other half would be guards.
the researchers then set up a basement at stanford to make it look like a real prison they
were very serious about treating the experiment like a simulation prisoners were actually arrested
in public and taken into prison they were even booked fingerprinted and strip searched now
zimbardo's team also gave prisoners numbers that were meant to be used instead of their real
name they claimed that it would help give the prisoners a sense of anonymity and help the experiment
Guards had pretty much free reign over how they could treat the prisoners, although they had
two main rules. They could not hit the prisoners, and they could not put prisoners in solitary
confinement for more than an hour.
Philip Zimbardo played the role of the prison superintendent.
His graduate students and research partners also played roles as members of the parole board
and the prison warden. Prisoners were tasked with certain activities like writing a letter
home to their visitors and making a case to the parole board about why they should be let off.
Guards also subjected the prisoners to counts in which they forced the prisoners to do jumping
jacks, push-ups, and other degrading tasks.
Now, it did not take long for these guards to start to abuse their power.
Within one day, a guard actually hit one of the prisoners with his nightstick.
On the second day, the prisoners tried to rebel, and so their beds were taken away.
To punish these prisoners, the guards shot a fire extinguisher into the cell.
Guards used physical and psychological abuse, including things like sleep deprivation, to punish
and intimidate the prisoners throughout the study.
The prisoners were forced to wear dressings and stocking caps the whole time.
And at some point, the guards would put bags over the prisoners' heads.
And since the study has ended, it has since been compared to actions at the Abu Ghraib Detention
Center. Zimbardo has written about the case and its parallels to the prison experiment since.
So why did this experiment get shut down?
Well, very quickly the guards started to abuse their power.
The prisoners started to spiral.
On the third day, prisoner number 8612 started to cry and scream uncontrollably.
He threatened to harm himself and call a lawyer.
To avoid potential psychological damage or a lawsuit, he was let go.
Two other prisoners were let go in the next two days.
One actually refused to eat.
And on the fifth day, Zimbardo's girlfriend, which was actually his former student, came to
visit the experiment. Zimbardo and his team had been monitoring the experiment and playing
their roles in it 24-7. And when she saw the horrors that was going on in the prison, she asked
Zimbardo to end the experiment immediately.
She even threatened to break up with him.
Well, eventually, on the sixth day, he ended the experiment.
This experiment showed the world how quickly people can abuse power when it's given to them,
but it remains as one of the most controversial experiments in the world of psychology, and
there's a few reasons why.
The first one is obvious, and it's the case for psychological abuse that the prisoners endured
during the study. Is it ethical to put human subjects through that kind of distress and trauma,
so much so that many couldn't even endure the experiment?
Now, Zimbardo claims that none of the participants have suffered long-term psychological consequences,
but the point still stands.
And in more recent years, critics have come forward to say that the results were not as natural
as Zimbardo and their team may want you to think.
Transcripts and audio recordings from the Stamford Prison Experiment show that Zimbardo's team
coached these guards. They told them to be tough for the sake of the experiment.
Even the prisoners may have been faking their responses.
prisoner number 8612, who is most well-known for his blood-curdling quote, I'm burning up inside.
He has come forward to say that his time in the Stanford County Jail was more of an improv
exercise. Many critics have likened the experiment to a drama rather than a legitimate psychology
experiment. Carlo Prescott, the experiment's prison consultant, has also come forward to say
that the experiment's more cruel treatments were not naturally thought up and executed by the
guards alone. He wrote,
Okay, guys, I hope you all watched it.
And okay, I hope my screen is okay.
Let me double check.
Yes, it seems okay.
And if you guys want to know more about this
experiment, there are also longer videos.
And as this video claimed, there is also a kind of a movie.
I mean, the real Hollywood movie about this
experiment, okay? I mean, you can watch, I mean, if you are really interested and have time,
okay?
And the point is, like many people will uncritically follow the commands of those in power,
right? And
therefore, I mean,
we may also have similar experiences in our lives, right?
Maybe not in that level, right?
Like in this, both
experiments, right? with the Yale study and Stanford study, right?
But at least in a certain level, we may have had similar situations in our lives where kind
of we were tasked or commanded by those in power or by our superiors, right?
And maybe they gave us some tasks or some kind of...
They put us in certain situations that went...
against our
beliefs and kind of moral standards, right?
And
what did you do in such situations, guys?
I mean, if you had such situations, I mean, did you refuse or did you just do whatever you
were commanded? And if you did whatever you were commanded, I mean, how did you justify yourself?
Or vice versa, if you refused
to do what your superiors have ordered you, I mean, how did you kind of refuse it?
What kind of reasons and
arguments did you give to them?
And
now with this kind of cases in mind and these topics in mind, we're closely coming to
the topic of critical thinking, because these cases show us that the lack of
critical thinking skills can
negatively affect our lives, right?
And negatively affect our everyday decisions, right?
Sometimes if we don't have, let's say, similar critical thinking abilities, maybe
the people in power or maybe our family members or our friends or our kind of bosses,
our
employers, our friends, right?
They may try to kind of persuade their own
agendas on us right and later on let's say we may end up in some careers that we do not like
right or we may end up in certain universities that we do not like right or maybe what's worse
that we may end up in some families right in some kind of marriage that later on we kind of
kind of think about it hard right so therefore i mean the critical thinking abilities kind
of they're really important to have a kind of a better standard of living also, right?
And can you guys kind of post this video and think about what is critical thinking?
Okay, guys, I hope that you all had some opinions on this term, on this topic, right?
And let's see, I mean, how the book defines it.
So according to the book, the critical thinking is a collection of skills that we use every
day that are necessary for our full intellectual and
personal development. Okay, so they're not kind of just one skill, right, they're kind of
collection of several skills, right, that we'll learn later on.
And it requires learning how to think rather than what to think.
Okay. And there's also
a point of logic, right? Because critical thinking like logic requires good analytical skills
and logic is a part of critical thinking, okay?
And it's defined as the study of the methods and principles used in distinguishing correct
or good
arguments from bad or
incorrect ones, okay? And there's also
opinion. So how logic or critical thinking is different from opinion.
So when we say about opinion is a kind of a belief based solely on our personal feelings
rather than a reason or fact.
Okay.
And now let's talk about cognitive development in university students.
So here we're talking about
the study, the result of study conducted by education researcher William Perry
Jr. in the last century. He conducted the study on cognitive development with
college students and he wanted to understand the cognitive development of college
students. And even though he came up with several stages, but later on, the other researchers
kind of, they synced them into kind of these three levels, okay?
So first of all, when we are much younger,
we have a kind of stage of dualism, okay?
So here we are kind of, when we were kind of in the freshman years, for example,
we kind of tend to
assimilate knowledge and life experiences in a simplistic dualistic ways,
viewing something either right or wrong, either
good or bad.
And
here we may see knowledge as
something existing
outside of our kind of sphere.
And then we may tend to look to superior figures for the right answers, okay?
So I think that those in power, maybe your professor, maybe your parents, maybe those in
the
politics, right? Those in power, or the big guys, or the millionaires, billionaires, those
rich tech gurus, for example, they have the right answer, right?
And
however, also here, we have kind of in this stage, we kind of...
dualistic stage is most obvious when students confront a conflict.
Okay. Although they may be able to apply
critical thinking skills in the kind of more structured
classroom settings. However, when they go to outside, so they may have some difficulties in
applying these skills. Okay.
And here also in this stage, students may have
confirmation bias, okay?
And by this we mean at the dualistic stage of research seeking out only evidence that supports
their views and dismissing evidence that contradicts it, okay?
So we tend to look for kind of views or opinions or some research, maybe
papers or some facts that kind of
align with our own view, okay?
And
then we slowly, we may go to the next stage, okay?
So this is called relativism, okay?
Stage two, okay? Here, I mean, rather than accepting that ambiguity may be unavoidable
and that we need to make decisions despite uncertainty, okay?
Students at this relativist stage go to the
opposite,
extreme, okay? So they reject a dualistic worldview and instead maintain that all truth is
relative or just a matter of opinion, okay?
So people at this stage believe that stating your opinion
is the proper mode of expression and they look down on challenging others' opinions, okay?
However, despite their
belief in relativism, most students at this stage still expect their professor
to support their opinion, okay?
So here, in short, by relativism,
we may say that
there is no truth. There are no true facts, right?
There is no objective reality.
We may say that
everything is relative, right?
That everybody have their own opinions, and therefore, I mean,
I may have my own opinion.
You may have your own opinion.
Therefore, there is no real truth, okay?
So this is the, I mean, nature of this relativist perspective or relativist worldview.
And the next stage, I mean, the much higher stage is commitment, okay?
So when students get mature, okay, they come to realize that not all thinking is
equally valid, okay? And not only can...
those in power authorities be mistaken but also in some circumstances uncertainty and
ambiguity are unavoidable okay
and when students at this stage experience uncertainty and they are now able to make decisions
and commit to particular positions on the basis of reason okay and the best evidence available
okay so this is kind of a maturity stage right here we come to realize
that
things are not kind of easy and sometimes things can be kind of
ambiguous in real life and this is okay.
And therefore, I mean, based on kind of certain facts or based on
better
arguments or better reason, we kind of set on certain points or on certain kind of
size, right?
Okay, so if this is the point with this critical thinking, and what about the
characteristics of a good critical thinker?
So can you guys pause this video and think about it?
Okay, guys, thank you very much.
I hope you all had some
good, great opinions about it.
And
critical thinking, like we mentioned before, is not just a single skill, right?
It's a kind of a collection of skills that enhance and reinforce each other, okay?
So here, some of the kind of
sets of these critical
thinking skills, okay, characteristics, such as analytical skills, effective communication,
research and inquiry skills, and let's kind of discuss them one by one.
So first of all, as a critical thinker, you need to be able to
analyze and provide a logical support for your beliefs rather than relying on your own
kind of opinion or on your own experiences.
Okay.
Therefore, analytical skills are important in recognizing and evaluating other people's opinions,
other people's arguments, so that you're not taken in by faulty reasoning.
Second one is effective communication.
Of course,
skills in writing, speaking, listening are necessary in order to be a good critical thinker
and will not
talk in detail about this one because
we learned this last year right in our engineering and business communication class and the
next one is the research and inquiry skills of course this research skills is also important
because whenever we want to kind of
analyze the situation we want to kind of come to a better conclusion, of course, we need to
do research, right? We need to kind of look for the facts, look for certain information, right?
And therefore, this type of skills are also important to be a better critical thinker.
And the next one is flexibility and tolerance through ambiguity, okay?
So this is an also important skill, okay?
Because sorting through the various claims and evidence involves discernment and tolerance
for ambiguity on the part of the critical thinker.
Too many people defer to others or fail to take a position on a controversial issue simply
because they are unable to evaluate conflicting views.
So therefore, we need to be flexible.
We need to be kind of patient.
And we need to be able to thrive on some
ambiguous situations, okay?
And the next point is open-minded skepticism, okay?
So critical thinkers are willing to work toward overcoming personal prejudices and biases,
and they begin with an open mind and an
attitude of reflective skepticism, okay?
This is also called the method of doubt, okay?
Which was kind of the term coined by a French philosopher, René Descartes, Okay.
And here, I mean, in the method of doubt, rather than accepting the opinions or ideas
on their face value, we just approach it from the side of skepticism,
right? We kind of approach the situation on the
on the face of a kind of
skeptic, right? Skepticism, right?
Rather than just simply believing the situation, we kind of want the situation or
the point or the person who is kind of
raising this issue to prove the situation, to prove the point to be true, okay?
So this is called the method of doubt.
And the next point is
creative problem solving.
Creative thinkers can view problems from multiple
perspectives and they come up with original solutions to complex problems.
They may use their imagination
and to kind of foresee certain kind of scenarios.
when we are kind of trying to use our creative thinking and we're trying to foresee the situation
kind of
beforehand, kind of we can be better prepared for the situation, right?
And creativity also involves a willingness to take risks, okay?
To cope with the unexpected, to welcome challenge and even a failure as a part of the process
to arrive at the new and deeper understanding, okay?
And the next characteristics is
attentive, mindful, and curious that critical thinkers should be, okay?
And here, like critical thinkers, usually they're intellectually curious, okay?
And they're attentive and mindful to what's going on around them, okay?
And to their own thoughts and feelings, okay?
And the next one is
collaborative learning, okay?
And here by collaborative learning, we do not just mean
that you need to learn or study something together with someone.
We are not meaning it in the literally terms, okay?
So critical thinking occurs in the real life context and anticipate the reaction of others,
right? Because usually when we want to exercise our critical thinking abilities, it means that
we are in some social situation, right?
We are kind of in interaction with some other people.
whether it be our family members,
our colleagues, our friends, or someone outside in the street, right?
So it means that in such situations, kind of we should be open to learn, right?
We should be open to listen to the opinions and ideas of other people.
And then based on this, I mean,
evaluate the situation and maybe sometimes maybe lower some of our barriers, right?
And try to kind of come up with the solutions that can be beneficial for both sides, right?
Okay,
now
let's imagine now, you know,
what critical thinking means and you know some of the good characteristics of
critical thinkers, right?
And you try your best to be a better critical thinker.
But what about that sometimes there may be certain barriers or certain challenges that may
kind of make your critical thinking
much harder, right? So can you guys pause this video and think about some of the barriers to
critical thinking?
Okay, guys, thank you very much.
So
there may be certain barriers
that can kind of hinder your abilities of critical thinking.
And here, let's start from the first one here.
The authors of the book, they developed this model, which is a three-time model of thinking,
okay?
And the
processes used in critical thinking can be broken down into three types of levels.
As you can see, first experience, interpretation, and analysis.
Let's talk about them one by one.
First of all, in the first level, we have a certain situation, certain experience, that
something happened, certain event.
certain facts, right? For example, you went to a job interview and you were rejected.
Or maybe you saw some news in the internet or on TV, right?
That saying that the
proportion of young people participating in
voting in the political events is decreasing, right?
So this is experience.
And the second one is called interpretation.
So here it involves trying to make sense of that experience, okay?
So you saw the experience or you had the experience itself, and then you kind of
try to make sense of that experience, right?
And some of our interpretations may be well informed, whereas others may be based solely on
our own opinion. or on our own personal feelings or prejudices or previous
experiences, right? So for example,
that after getting rejected from this job interview, you may say that I didn't get the job
because I didn't have maybe the right connections, okay?
Or regarding this decreasing number of young voters, you may say that
The reason for this is because nowadays young people, they are not interested in politics,
right? So you may kind of try to make sense of this experience like this.
And the last point is analysis.
Here it requires that we raise our level of thinking and critically examine our interpretation
of that experience, right?
As well as those others, right?
Refusing to accept either narrow interpretations often experiences or interpretations that
are too broad, okay? And usually this step
requires us asking questions, okay?
For example, in the case of this job rejection, you can ask yourself that was it because of
your
lack of connections or maybe because of your lack of experience or maybe
your kind of skills on this job interview, right?
or also regarding these
young voters, right? You can ask yourself
why this happened.
I mean, what could be the real causes or the real reasons for this, right?
I mean, what can be the real interest of young people nowadays, right?
Rather than coming to
simplistic answers, you try to ask some questions and try to go to the
deeper meaning or the deeper reasons or deeper points of this
experience. The next set of barriers to
critical thinking is called resistance.
Because most of us
don't like
to be proven wrong, we may create barriers
to keep our
cherish the world views from being challenged.
And resistance here is defined as the habitual use of immature defense mechanisms
when our world views are challenged.
And here are some of the kind of
types of resistance such as avoidance, anger,
cliches, denial, ignorance, conformity, struggling and distractions.
So here, I mean,
I will not
be discussing them one by one.
So this will be your job, maybe to think about it and maybe to
research about it, right?
To find about it. I mean, if you don't know the meanings of these words, I mean, you can find
out from dictionaries, from online dictionaries.
And also after finding out the meaning, you just need to try to connect them
to this critical thinking barrier.
This will be your task. Let me just comment on the struggling point.
It may be normal sometimes
to struggle
on certain issues when you're trying to analyze the situation.
However, some people get so caught up in the details and what-ifs often
issue or situation, right?
And then they may kind of, they may accomplish nothing and they may lose time, right?
And the procrastinators are also most likely to use this type of resistance, right?
Struggling. Okay. And all those struggling with an issue as part of the analytical process
of coming up with a resolution and plan for action is an important kind of a part of critical
thinking, right? But when the struggle becomes an end itself, right, we are engaging in
resistance, not critical thinking.
Okay, just give me a, let me give you an example.
Like recently, I think last week, we had this terrible accident happened in Nepal, right?
There was some kind of mudfall, right?
And you may have heard about this case of this person
school director, right?
He kind of evacuated about 900 students, 900 pupils from school in a very kind of
short amount of time, right?
So just imagine, like he also pointed, right, if he were late for about 10 minutes, right,
maybe they all would die, right?
So kind of he made a quick decision, right?
He kind of didn't struggle with this thinking.
I mean, he, based on certain facts, he made a very quick decision, he realized that the situation
was very serious, and he acted immediately, right?
And he could save the lives of these 900 people, right?
So, okay, I mean, the rest will be your task, okay, to think about it.
And the next set of barriers to critical thinking is called narrow-mindedness, okay?
And by narrow-mindedness, we mean the rigid beliefs
that interfere with the critical analysis of our worldviews.
And here also, there are certain kind of points of this narrow-mindedness, such as
absolutism, fear of challenge, eco-centrism, ethnocentrism, and fascism.
anthropocentrism. And this will be also your task.
I mean, I will not be discussing them one by one.
So this will be a task. I just go to internet and try to find out the meanings of these kind
of terms and try to connect them to critical thinking barrier.
And here are some more
barriers to critical thinking such as rationalization and doublethink,
cognitive and social dissonance and stress.
So also
try to find out the meanings of these terms and try to connect them to a barrier
of critical thinking, okay?
Try to think about it, okay?
So this will be a task, guys.
So this was all for
these chapters and for today's lectures, okay guys?
Here in the conclusion, I just want to point out
something that
since I mean, in the first video, I forgot to mention, since we have quizzes, right, we have
some part of the grade, and sometimes right after these online lectures, I'll be posting
some quizzes
on the eClass.
And also, as I mentioned, we should be using our own mind, our own senses, our own kind of
judgment to
for this class,
I want to ask you guys
to complete these quizzes by yourself.
And therefore, I will do my best to not give you just simplistic quizzes where you can just
be choosing from multiple choice questions or finding from internet, right?
Rather, I'll be giving you questions kind of which will require your own thoughts, your own
opinions, which means there are no
right or wrong answers, right?
So even though we are going to relativism here, still, I mean, because this is a,
this will be your own judgment, your own opinions.
The questions will be asking about your own experiences, right?
So therefore,
these guys don't go to internet, don't use Google, don't use these AI tools, okay?
Just you use your own judgment, okay?
So which means
for all people for all those who will be using their own judgments and giving certain ideas,
right? Based on their own experiences, based on their own kind of answers, you'll get full
points for these quiz questions, okay?
So I'll not be kind of reading them in detail, but I'll be just looking them that if you wrote
them
based on your own words, okay?
So therefore, please, I mean, you don't have pressure, right?
I mean, don't have pressure to make it right.
100%. Therefore, don't use chat GPT, just spend at least five or 10 minutes on this each
quizzes and try to come up with your own ideas.
Okay, because as I said, this is the real opportunity to exercise your own mind and your own
judgment, and eventually try to please develop, maybe on certain level, our thinking and
critical thinking abilities, because writing is also thinking, right?
Okay, guys, with these points in mind, we'll finish our first lecture.
See you guys next week.